us1.com 2019-12-04

# Privacy statement | Russell Investments

Privacy statement for russellinvestments.com

Russell Investments has a firm commitment to privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for this Web site: russellinvestments.com. The Privacy and Security notice (PDF) of Russell Investments covers these issues in further detail.

We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our Web site. Your IP address is used to gather broad demographic information. We use cookies to deliver content specific to your interests, to save your password so you don't have to re-enter it each time you visit our site, and for other purposes.

Our site's registration forms and surveys request users to give us contact information (e.g. their name, phone number, e-mail and mailing address) and limited financial information (e.g. assets under management and investible assets). We use contact information to send the user requested information about our company. The information is also used to contact the visitor when necessary. Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt-out section below. The data collected is used to tailor the visitor's experience at our site, showing them content that we think they might be interested in, and displaying the content according to their preferences.

This site contains links to other sites. Russell Investments is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites.

Security

This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control.

Choice/opt-out

Our site provides users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us at the point where we request information about the visitor.

This site gives users the following options for removing their information from our database to stop future communications or to no longer receive our service.

You can send e-mail to [webmaster@russellinvestments.com](mailto:webmaster@russellinvestments.com).

Correct/update

This site gives users the following options for changing and modifying information previously provided.

You can send e-mail to [webmaster@russellinvestments.com](mailto:webmaster@russellinvestments.com).

Cookies 

By modifying your browser preferences, you have the choice to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is set or to reject all cookies. However, you should be aware that if cookies are rejected you will not be able to use some of the online services provided by Russell Investments. For more information on how to configure your browser preferences, please refer to the user guides:

A full list of all cookies Russell Investments uses can be found here .

Cookies for storing your preferences

We use various cookies to store some details you enter and choices you make so that we do not have to ask you for them every time you visit a page that needs them.

Cookie name | Purpose  
---|---  
ASP.NET_SessionId,  
ASPSESSIONID******** | Keeps a record of your current Russell Investments session so that we can provide consistent functionality across the site.  It expires when you logout, close your browser or if you clear your cache of browsing history.

ASPSESSIONID******** will generate a random set of 8 letters that will change with every session.   
  
ri.com | This will remember your preferences from the russellinvestments.com so your preferences will persist on future visits. These preferences include: country selection; audience type selection; acceptance of cookies.  
website#lang | This will remember your language preference from the russellinvestments.com so your preference will persist on future visits.  
  
Cookies for improving service by measuring traffic

We use Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, in order to find out how visitors interact with Russell Investments so we can improve it. Information is collected anonymously and website trends are reported without identifying individual visitors.

Cookie name | Purpose  
---|---  
__utma | Keeps track of the number of times a visitor has been to the site, when their first visit was, and when their last visit occurred. It expires after two years.  
__utmb and __utmc | The B and C cookies work together to calculate how long a visit takes.

__utmb takes a timestamp of the exact moment in time when a visitor enters a site, while __utmc takes a timestamp of the exact moment in time when a visitor leaves a site.

__utmc has no way of knowing when a user closes their browser or leaves a website, so it waits 30 minutes for another pageview to happen, and if it doesn't, it expires.  
  
__utmz | Keeps track of where the visitor came from, what search engine was used, what link was clicked on, what keyword was used, and where they were in the world when the website was accessed.  
_ga | Used by Google to distinguish users.   
_gac | Used by Google to store campaign information for AdWords.  
_gat_*** | This cookie is used with Google Universal Analytics. This cookie is used to monitor and track visitors behavior on the site anonymously.  
auto | Used by Google to distinguish users.  
ELOQUA, ELQSTATUS | These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. This information is used to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited. If you click through to our website from an email sent by Eloqua, we are subsequently able to identify the pages you visit on russellinvestments.com. This information is stored securely in Eloqua and never, under any circumstances, supplied to third parties.  
VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE, PREF, YSC | We use YouTube to embed videos. The VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE cookie attempts to estimate your bandwidth. The PREF cookie may be used by YouTube to store session preferences that relate to your activity when watching the embedded videos. These cookies don't gather information that identifies a user.  
SC_ANALYTICS_GLOBAL_COOKIE | This cookie is used to identify repeat visits from a single user  
Demandbase (from company-target.com) | This cookie is used to track the number of users & companies that have visited a website and conversions. That cookie pool can then be used to retarget those users/companies, and serve them digital ad units. It also collects non-personal identifiable business demographic data for a user (non PII). This is a Third Party Persistent cookie with a duration of 2 years. Opt out of this cookie at <https://d.company-target.com/opt-out>.  
6siuuid,  _gd_svisitor, _gd_visitor | This cookie is used to monitor and track visitors behavior on the site anonymously.  It collects information from visitors such as Internet protocol address, cookie identifiers, mobile advertising identifiers, and other device identifiers that are automatically assigned to the computer or device of a visitor as well as site usage information such as pages visited, the date and time of the visit, the amount of time spent on each page and other behaviors on the site. Russel Investment could use this information for account marketing to prospective customers, including to track conversions and serve digital ads.  
  
DoubleClick (A Google Company) cookies

We also may use DoubleClick cookies for ad serving through Google’s DoubleClick, which places a cookie on your computer when you are browsing the web and visit a site using DoubleClick advertising (including some Google AdSense advertisements). This cookie is used to serve ads specific to you and your interests (”interest based targeting”). The ads served will be targeted based on your previous browsing history. DoubleClick uses “non personally identifiable information”. It does NOT track personal information about you, such as your name, email address, physical address, telephone number, social security numbers, bank account numbers or credit card numbers. You can opt-out of this ad serving on all sites using this advertising by visiting <http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/dart_adserving.aspx>

The LinkedIn Insight Tag

This tag enables the collection of data regarding members’ visits to your website, including the URL, referrer, IP address, device and browser characteristics (User Agent), and timestamp. This data is encrypted, the IP addresses are truncated, and members’ direct identifiers are removed within seven days in order to make the data pseudonymous. This remaining, pseudonymized data is then deleted within 90 days.

LinkedIn does not share the personal data with the website owner, it only provides aggregated reports about the website audience and ad performance. LinkedIn also provides retargeting for website visitors, enabling the website owner to show personalized ads off its website by using this data, but without identifying the member. LinkedIn members can control the use of their personal data for advertising purposes [through their account settings](https://www.linkedin.com/psettings/advertising/actions-that-showed-interest).

Contacting the Web site

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact

Webmaster  
Russell Investments  
1301 Second Avenue  
18th Floor  
Seattle, WA 98101  
206-505-7877 (206-505-RUSSELLINVESTMENTS)  
1-800-426-7969
